Guide to the Robert Mearns Yerkes Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Experiments, 1900-1953; Series III; 2.75 linear feet (7 boxes)
  Series III, EXPERIMENTS, is housed in Boxes 114-120 of the Robert M. Yerkes Papers. It consists of notes and logs on chimpanzee and gorilla research plus a variety of other materials, including announcements, syllabi, test cards, and instructions, and bound typescripts.
  - notebooks, etc.
    - Chimpanzees
      - Record books on Chim and Panzee, 1923-1924 (Box 114, Folder 2139-2140)
      - Accounts, 1924-1927 (Box 114, Folder 2141)
      - Classification of Chimpanzee materials, Circa 1927 (Box 114, Folder 2142)
    - Gorillas
      - notes on gorilla Congo, 1925-1928 (Box 114, Folder 2143-2147)
      - Sample of Congo's hair, 1927 (Box 115, Folder 2148)
      - Typescript of notes on Gorilla Congo, 1927 (Box 115, Folder 2149-2159)
  - notes on experiments
    - Physical measurements of chimpanzees, 1924-1929 (Box 115, Folder 2160)
    - Multiple choice experiment, 1926 (Box 115, Folder 2161)
    - Mechanical abilities: chimps, 1926 (Box 115, Folder 2162-2163)
    - Mirror, box stacking, box and pole, 1931-1932 (Box 116, Folder 2164)
    - Delayed response, 1927 (Box 116, Folder 2165-2166)
    - Chimpanzee, indirect course, 1928 (Box 116, Folder 2167)
    - Memory experiments, 1928-1929 (Box 116, Folder 2168)
    - Platform and stick, box and pole, 1931-1932 (Box 116, Folder 2169)
    - Multiple choice, 1932-1933 (Box 116, Folder 2170-2171)
    - Grooming notes, 1931-1933 (Box 117, Folder 2172)
    - Billy, Dwina, Pan, and Wendy, undated (Box 117, Folder 2173)
  - Research: Test Materials
    - Thumb index inquiry, 1952-1953 (Box 117, Folder 2174-2179)
  - Announcements of Institute of Psychology of Yale University, 1925-1930 (Box 117, Folder 2180)
  - Pro-Seminar syllabi, 1932-1941 (Box 118, Folder 2181-2185)
  - Harvard Psychological Laboratory; test cards and instructions, undated (Box 118, Folder 2186)
  - Bound Typescripts
    - The Biojonnismith, 1900-1901 (Box 118, Folder 2187)
    - "An Experimental Study of the Reactions of the Medusa Gonionema murbachii to Photic and Electric Stimuli" by Romby, undated (Box 119, Folder 2188)
    - "Auditory-Tactual Reinforcement and Inhibition in the Frog" by C.J. Blix, 1905 (Box 119, Folder 2189)
    - "The Physiology of the Senses and the Behavior of the Dancing Mouse" by Romby, 1907 (Box 119, Folder 2190)
  - Journal of Animal Behavior & Behavior Monographs; accounts, 1910-1923 (Box 119, Folder 2191)
  - Laboratory log, 1925-1942 (Box 120, Folder 2192)
- Writings, 1893-1965; Series IV; 4.25 linear feet (10 boxes)
  Series IV, WRITINGS, fills boxes 121-130 of the Yerkes Papers and is divided into two sections, Books and Papers. Books are located in Boxes 121-127 and the books are arranged chronologically by date of publication. Papers, Boxes 127-130, contains nine bound volumes of chronologically arranged articles and reviews by Robert M. and Ada Watterson Yerkes and a final volume containing oversize items, articles about Yerkes, and pieces printed after the death of Yerkes.
  - Books
    - Psychology by John Dewey, 1893 (Box 121, Folder 2193)
    - Hypnotism and Hypnotic Suggestion, ed. by E. Virgil Neal and Charles S. Clark, 1900 (Box 121, Folder 2194)
    - The Dancing Mouse, 1907 (Box 121, Folder 2195)
    - Introduction to Psychology and newspaper clippings, 1911 (Box 121, Folder 2196)
    - A Point Scale for Measuring Mental Ability by Robert M. Yerkes, James W. Bridges, and Rose S. Hardwick, 1915 (Box 122, Folder 2197)
    - The Harvey Lectures 1917-19 by W.T. Porter et al., 1920 (Box 122, Folder 2198)
    - Army Mental Tests ed. by Clarence S. Yoakum and Robert M. Yerkes, 1920 (Box 122, Folder 2199)
    - Psychological Examining in the U.S. Army Vol. XV of Memoirs of the National Academy of Sciences, 1921 (Box 122, Folder 2200)
    - Almost Human, 1925 (Box 123, Folder 2201)
    - Chimpanzee Intelligence and its Vocal Expressions by Robert M. Yerkes and Blanche W. Learned, 1925 (Box 123, Folder 2202)
    - The Mind of a Gorilla, 1926-1928 (Box 123, Folder 2203)
    - "Relation of Anthropoid Research to Social Science," Hanover Conference, Social Science Research Council, 1927 (Box 124, Folder 2204)
    - The Great Apes by Robert M. Yerkes and Ada W. Yerkes, 1929 (Box 124, Folder 2205)
    - The Great Apes manuscript, 1929 (Box 124, Folder 2206-2207)
    - The Great Apes manuscript, 1929 (Box 125, Folder 2208-2216)
    - The Great Apes manuscript, 1929 (Box 126, Folder 2217-2218)
    - Chimpanzees, A Laboratory Colony, 1943 (Box 126, Folder 2219)
    - The Selection of Military Manpower. A Symposium ed. by Leonard Carmichael and Leonard C. Mead, 1951 (Box 126, Folder 2220)
    - The Uses of the Past by Herbert J. Muller, 1952 (Box 126, Folder 2221)
    - Twenty-five Years of Sex Research by Sophie D. Aberle and George W. Corner, 1953 (Box 126, Folder 2222)
    - An Experimental Study of Sensation by Edwin B. Holt and Robert M. Yerkes, 1903 (Box 127, Folder 2223)
    - Tables of Organization U.S. Army, 1917 (Box 127, Folder 2224)
    - Outline of a Study of the Self by Robert M. Yerkes and Daniel W. LaRue, 1913 (Box 127, Folder 2225)
  - Papers
    - Robert M. Yerkes and Ada W. Yerkes, 1899-1910 (Box 127, Folder 2226-2227)
    - Robert M. Yerkes and Ada W. Yerkes, 1911-1920 (Box 128, Folder 2228-2229)
    - Robert M. Yerkes and Ada W. Yerkes, 1921-1935 (Box 129, Folder 2230-2232)
    - Robert M. Yerkes, 1936-1956 (Box 130, Folder 2233-2234)
    - Robert M. Yerkes, larger or late papers, 1935-1965 (Box 130, Folder 2235)
- Photographs, 1867-1972; Series V; 7.5 linear feet (15 boxes)
  Series V. PHOTOGRAPHS, consists of six boxes of professional and nine boxes of personal photographs. Professional photographs are located in Boxes 131-136. Boxes 131-132 hold photograph albums mostly containing pictures of chimpanzees and gorillas. The other boxes have additional chimpanzee and gorilla photographs, book illustrations, World War I photos, and miscellaneous other pictures. Personal photographs are found in Boxes 137-145 and consist primarily of photo albums. Boxes 138-143 held eleven albums comprising the photographic collection of Ada Watterson Yerkes and boxes 143-145 contain five albums of the photographic collection of Roberta Yerkes Blanshard.
  - Professional
    - Photograph albums
      - Chim and Panzee, 1923-1924 (Box 131, Folder 2236)
      - Abreu Primate Colony, Havana, Cuba, 1924 (Box 131, Folder 2237)
      - Congo, 1925-1928 (Box 131, Folder 2238)
      - Chimpanzees: Billy, Dwina, Pam, Wendy, 1925-1926 (Box 132, Folder 2239)
      - Kindia and Russia, 1929 (Box 132, Folder 2240)
      - Montecito Laboratory, Santa Barbara, CA, 1915 (Box 132, Folder 2241)
    - The Great Apes illustrations, Circa 1929 (Box 133, Folder 2242-2258)
    - Friends and colleagues, 1936-1953, undated (Box 133, Folder 2259)
    - Sleeping posture of chimps: sketches and notes by David Yerkes, 1927 (Box 133, Folder 2260)
    - Gorillas, San Diego Zoo: Al, Bo, and Ba, 1952 (Box 133, Folder 2261-2262)
    - Yerkes Laboratories of Primate Biology, slides, 1972 (Box 133, Folder 2263)
    - Ape and child by H.C. Raven, 1933 (Box 134, Folder 2264)
    - Various chimps: Fin and Finch children, 1940 (Box 134, Folder 2265-2266)
    - Yerkes Laboratories of Primate Biology apes, 1940 (Box 134, Folder 2267)
    - Study of Behavior of pig, undated (Box 134, Folder 2268)
    - Directions and illustrative materials for A Point Scale, undated (Box 134, Folder 2269)
    - Committee on Psychological Examination of Recruits, 1917 (Box 134, Folder 2270)
    - Army photo, Psychological Co. No. 1, WWI, 1918 (Box 134, Folder 2271)
    - Sketch of Panzee by David Yerkes, age 11, reproduced in Almost Human, 1923 (Box 134, Folder 2272)
    - Congo in The Mind of a Gorilla, 1927 (Box 134, Folder 2273-2274)
    - Thorndike Puzzle-Box Apparatus (Animal Intelligence), 1926-1972
      See: box 47, folder 920
    - Hayes: Viki; fingerpainting, bath, 1949-1950 (Box 134, Folder 2275)
    - Mother Infant Relationship in Chimpanzee, Yerkes and Tomilin, undated (Box 134, Folder 2276)
    - Exhibit at American Psychological Association, negatives, 1975 (Box 134, Folder 2277)
    - "On the Side of the Apes" by Emily Hahn, negatives, undated (Box 134, Folder 2278)
    - Three rolls of World War I photographs, 1918 (Box 135)
    - Engraving of F.E.D. Schleiermacher, 1867 (Box 136, Folder 2279)
    - Borneo by Dr. Gregor Krause, undated (Box 136, Folder 2280-2282)
    - Plates of Prof. Bischoff, 1897 (Box 136, Folder 2283)
    - Cartoon by Hooton, undated (Box 136, Folder 2284)
    - Watercolor by David N. Yerkes: Laboratory, Orange Park, Fla., 1930 (Box 136, Folder 2285)
    - Japanese print: gift from Edward L. Thorndike, undated (Box 136, Folder 2286)
    - Sketches of chimp head by Watagin, 1934 (Box 136, Folder 2287)
  - Personal
    - List of People in Bound photo album: Addis Carrell relatives, and others, undated (Box 137, Folder 2288)
    - Bound photo album, undated (Box 137, Folder 2289)
    - Dellenback photos of Robert M. Yerkes, 1952 (Box 137, Folder 2290)
    - Negatives and glossies of Robert M. and Ada W. Yerkes, undated (Box 137, Folder 2291)
    - Robert M. Yerkes: at various periods: Harvard, Washington, and New Haven, Circa 1917-1954 (Box 137, Folder 2292)
    - W. Reynolds Vance, 1932 (Box 137, Folder 2293)
    - Folio: Franklin, N.H., Mary Richmond, Montecito, CA., 1915, undated (Box 138, Folder 2294)
    - Robert M. Yerkes: photo for Saturday Evening Post, 1947 (Box 138, Folder 2295)
    - Photographic Collection of Ada Watterson Yerkes
      - Vol. 1: California, 1915 (Box 138, Folder 2296)
      - Vol. 2: Woods Hole and Cambridge, 1900-1905 (Box 138, Folder 2296)
      - Vol. 3: Europe, Cambridge, Franklin, N.H., 1902, 1905, 1914 (Box 138, Folder 2297)
      - Vol. 4: Yerkes family, 1890's-1929 (Box 139, Folder 2298)
      - Vol. 5: Yerkes family, European trip and Orange Park, Fla., 1929-1932 (Box 140, Folder 2299)
      - Vol. 6: Yerkes family, Florida and family pictures, 1932-1934 (Box 140, Folder 2300)
      - Vol. 7: Yerkes family, Florida, and friends, 1934-1939 (Box 141, Folder 2301)
      - Vol. 8: Yerkes family, 1939-1944 (Box 141, Folder 2302)
      - Vol. 9: Yerkes family, relatives, Circa 1892-1901 (Box 142, Folder 2303)
      - Vol. 11: Yerkes family, 1943-1953 (Box 142, Folder 2304)
      - Vol. 12: Yerkes family, 1955-1961 (Box 143, Folder 2305)
    - Photographic Collection of Roberta Yerkes Blanshard
      - Vol. 1: Yerkes family life in Washington, D.C. and Franklin, N.H., 1917-1922 (Box 143, Folder 2306)
      - Vol. 2: Yerkes family, 1912-1941 (Box 144, Folder 2307)
      - Vol. 3: Yerkes family, 1935-1940 (Box 144, Folder 2308)
      - Vol. 4: Yerkes family, 1941-1948 (Box 145, Folder 2309)
      - Vol. 5: Yerkes family, 1947-1957 (Box 145, Folder 2310)
      - Loose photographs of Yerkes family members, 1899, 1938, undated (Box 145, Folder 2311)
- Personal Papers, 1822-1965; Series VI; 21.5 linear feet (35 boxes)
  PERSONAL PAPERS, Boxes 146-180, is divided into the following sections: Autobiographical, Box 146; Biographical, Boxes 146-157; Insurance, Box 157; Miscellaneous Business, Box 157; Organizations, Boxes 157-158; Real Estate, Boxes 158-159; Family, Boxes 159-165; Family: Relatives, Boxes 165-168; Diaries, Boxes 169-177; and Oversize, Boxes 178-180.
  The Biographical section contains memoirs, obituaries, and reminiscences of Robert M. Yerkes in Box 147, and is followed by extensive files of chronologically arranged material documenting Yerkes' years at Ursinus College, Boxes 147-150; Harvard University, Boxes 150-155; and Woods Hole, Boxes 155-156. In the part designated Family, material is arranged alphabetically by family member and then chronologically. Likewise, the section Family: Relatives is divided alphabetically by family and then chronologically. The Diaries section contains forty volumes of diaries and journals kept by Robert M. Yerkes from 1891 to 1954, followed by a small group of diaries of Ada Watterson Yerkes. Oversize material consists of a sound recording of baby gorilla noises, a microfilm copy of Yerkes-E.B. Titchener correspondence located at Cornell University, and a trunk and charts of World War I psychological testing materials.
  - Autobiographical
    - Typescript of "Testament", undated (Box 146, Folder 2311-2317)
    - Bookplate: Yerkes, Robert M. and Ada W., undated (Box 146, Folder 2318)
    - "Creating a Chimpanzee Community", 1962 (Box 146, Folder 2319)
  - Biographical
    - Biographies in encyclopedias, 1941-1959 (Box 146, Folder 2320-2321)
    - Genealogy: ancestral tablet, undated (Box 146, Folder 2322)
    - Memoirs, 1956-1957 (Box 146, Folder 2323)
    - Memoirs, 1956-1965 (Box 147, Folder 2324)
    - Article for International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, 1962-1964 (Box 147, Folder 2325)
    - Obituaries, 1956 (Box 147, Folder 2326)
    - Life history, 1876-1956 (Box 147, Folder 2327)
    - Anthropometric measurements, 1904-1953 (Box 147, Folder 2328)
    - Bucks County Boyhood, 1954-1964 (Box 147, Folder 2329-2330)
    - Yerkes, William Augustus: reminiscences, 1965 (Box 147, Folder 2331)
    - "Snowshoes to School", 1899-1905 (Box 147, Folder 2332-2334)
    - Drawing book (Jacksonville School), 1890 (Box 147, Folder 2335)
    - Autograph album, 1885-1888 (Box 147, Folder 2336)
    - Accounts, 1891-1895 (Box 147, Folder 2337)
    - Aryan Society, West Chester State Normal School, 1891 (Box 147, Folder 2338)
    - Compositions: Academy at Collegeville, 1888-1893 (Box 147, Folder 2339)
    - Ursinus College
      - Scholarship and rejection of West Point appointment, 1893-1894 (Box 147, Folder 2340)
      - Course grades at academy and College, 1892-1897 (Box 147, Folder 2341)
      - The Ruby and College Handbook, 1896-1897 (Box 148, Folder 2342)
      - Schaff Literary Society and Gazette Constitutions, 1887-1894 (Box 148, Folder 2343)
      - Papers: "The Spirit of Modern Science" "Valedictory", 1893-1897 (Box 148, Folder 2344)
      - Drawing books, 1896 (Box 148, Folder 2345-2346)
      - Undergraduate notebooks, 1894-1897 (Box 148, Folder 2347-2350)
      - Undergraduate notebooks, 1894-1897 (Box 149, Folder 2351-2356)
      - Zoology drawing book, 1897 (Box 149, Folder 2357)
      - Themes, 1893-1896 (Box 149, Folder 2358-2360)
      - Themes, 1896-1897 (Box 150, Folder 2361)
      - Essays and exercises, undated (Box 150, Folder 2362)
      - Exams, 1896-1897 (Box 150, Folder 2363)
    - Harvard University
      - Application, 1897 (Box 150, Folder 2364)
      - Student bill, grades, exams, etc., 1898-1901 (Box 150, Folder 2365)
      - Fellowships, prizes, appointments, etc., 1898-1917 (Box 150, Folder 2366-2368)
      - First Forensic, 1897 (Box 150, Folder 2369)
      - Second Forensic, 1898 (Box 150, Folder 2370)
      - Third Forensic, 1898 (Box 150, Folder 2371)
      - Philosophy notebook, 1897-1902 (Box 150, Folder 2372)
      - Philosophy notebooks, 1897-1902 (Box 151, Folder 2373-2378)
      - Philosophy papers, 1897-1901, undated (Box 151, Folder 2379-2387)
      - Psychology notebooks, 1898-1901 (Box 152, Folder 2388-2395)
      - Psychology papers, 1901, undated (Box 152, Folder 2396-2397)
      - Zoology notebooks, 1897 (Box 152, Folder 2398-2400)
      - Zoology notebooks, 1897-1898 (Box 153, Folder 2401-2411)
      - Zoology notebooks, 1898-1899, undated (Box 154, Folder 2412-2420)
      - Zoology 3, Special Topic Work, 1898 (Box 154, Folder 2421)
      - Zoology papers, 1897-1898 (Box 154, Folder 2422-2423)
      - Zoology papers, 1897-1898 (Box 155, Folder 2424)
      - Zoology 15 papers, 1898 (Box 155, Folder 2425)
      - Zoology 16 papers, 1899 (Box 155, Folder 2426)
      - Zoology 2 papers, 1899 (Box 155, Folder 2427)
      - Zoology papers, 1900 (Box 155, Folder 2428)
      - Class of 1898, 1904-1962 (Box 155, Folder 2429-2434)
      - Class of 1898: The '98 Digest, 1954 (Box 155, Folder 2435)
    - Woods Hole
      - Animal Psychology notebooks, 1899-1901 (Box 155, Folder 2436-2438)
      - Comparative Physiology notebook, 1901 (Box 155, Folder 2439)
      - Neurological seminar papers, 1899 (Box 156, Folder 2440)
      - Observations; Gonionemus Book 1, 1900 (Box 156, Folder 2441)
      - Observations; Gonionemus Book 2, 1901 (Box 156, Folder 2442)
      - Observations; Medusae, 1900-1901 (Box 156, Folder 2443)
      - Observations; Green crab, 1901 (Box 156, Folder 2444)
    - Honorary degrees, 1923-1931 (Box 156, Folder 2445)
    - United States Army, 1917-1924 (Box 156, Folder 2446)
    - U.S. Public Health Service, 1935-1942 (Box 156, Folder 2447)
    - Scrapbook, 1899-1944 (Box 156, Folder 2448)
    - Germany: address book, 1902-1903 (Box 156, Folder 2449)
    - Germany: journal, 1902-1903 (Box 156, Folder 2450)
    - Address book, 1917-1918 (Box 156, Folder 2451)
    - Africa: accounts, 1929 (Box 156, Folder 2452)
    - World War II: address book, Circa 1941-1945 (Box 157, Folder 2453)
    - Address book, 1920-1950 (Box 157, Folder 2454)
    - Bust by Watagin, 1930-1931 (Box 157, Folder 2455)
    - Portrait by Clarence Brodeur, 1945-1947 (Box 157, Folder 2456)
    - Sketches, 1930 (Box 157, Folder 2457)
    - Yerkes Centennial Conference, 1976 (Box 157, Folder 2458)
  - Insurance
    - Miscellaneous, 1897-1953 (Box 157, Folder 2459)
    - Teachers Insurance and Annuity Association, 1931-1948 (Box 157, Folder 2460)
  - Miscellaneous Business
    - Automobiles (from Model T to Buick), 1919-1942 (Box 157, Folder 2461)
    - Babson Reports, 1938-1940 (Box 157, Folder 2462)
    - Book-of-the-Month Club, 1940-1946 (Box 157, Folder 2463)
    - Fur farming, 1913-1928, undated (Box 157, Folder 2464)
    - Memberships and subscriptions withdrawn, 1944-1949 (Box 157, Folder 2465)
  - Organizations
    - Brotherhood (A Union for Ethical Action), 1903-1909 (Box 157, Folder 2466)
    - Clubs, 1917-1956 (Box 157, Folder 2467)
    - Questioners (A Yale faculty club), 1929-1956 (Box 157, Folder 2468)
    - Wicht Club, 1900-1980 (Box 157, Folder 2469)
    - Contributions, 1927-1942 (Box 158, Folder 2470)
    - Miscellaneous memberships, 1931-1947 (Box 158, Folder 2471)
    - New Haven organizations, 1926-1948 (Box 158, Folder 2472)
    - Pennsylvania Society of Sons of the Revolution, 1927-1955 (Box 158, Folder 2473)
  - Real Estate
    - Woods Hole, 1906-1957 (Box 158, Folder 2474)
    - Franklin, N.H., 1911-1930 (Box 158, Folder 2475-2476)
    - Franklin, N.H.: Lewis H. Russell work on property, 1912-1948 (Box 158, Folder 2477-2479)
    - Franklin, N.H.: Accounts with Lewis Russell, 1913-1914 (Box 158, Folder 2480)
    - Franklin, N.H.: Painting and furnishing, 1912-1918 (Box 158, Folder 2481)
    - Franklin, N.H.: Farm expenses, 1911-1924 (Box 158, Folder 2482)
    - Franklin, N.H.: shingling, power, etc., 1913-1948 (Box 158, Folder 2483)
    - Franklin, N.H.: Mason, Everlin, and George Patten and Daniel Farnum, 1920-1963 (Box 159, Folder 2484)
    - Washington: purchase of 2065 Park Road, 1920-1924 (Box 159, Folder 2485)
    - Washington: sale of 2065 Park Road to Walton Hamilton, 1924-1927 (Box 159, Folder 2486)
    - New Haven: lease of Apt.631 Whitney Ave.; lot not purchased, 1925 (Box 159, Folder 2487)
  - Family
    - Yerkes genealogy, 1912-1948, undated (Box 159, Folder 2488-2489)
    - Yerkes, Ada Watterson
      - to Robert M. Yerkes, 1908-1924 (Box 159, Folder 2490-2494)
      - to Robert M. David, and Roberta Yerkes, 1928-1952 (Box 159, Folder 2495-2501)
      - Biographical, autograph book, 1882 (Box 159, Folder 2502)
      - Biographical, documents, 1873-1963 (Box 160, Folder 2503)
      - Biographical, botany at Barnard, 1896 (Box 160, Folder 2504)
      - Biographical, life in Cambridge, 1905-1917 (Box 160, Folder 2505)
      - Biographical, Franklin records, farm history, 1911-1917 (Box 160, Folder 2506)
      - Biographical, Franklin records, 1912-1931 (Box 160, Folder 2507-2508)
      - Biographical, Washington, D.C., 1918-1922 (Box 160, Folder 2509)
      - Biographical, New Haven social register, 1927-1963 (Box 160, Folder 2510)
      - Biographical, logs of trips, 1936-1959 (Box 160, Folder 2511)
      - Friends, Dana, Maria Trumbull, 1960-1962, undated (Box 160, Folder 2512)
      - Friends, Marple, Lucius and Martha, 1956-1957 (Box 160, Folder 2512A)
      - Friends, Morgan, Constance Morrow, 1955-1966 (Box 160, Folder 2513)
      - Friends, Morrow, Elizabeth Cutter, 1904-1955 (Box 160, Folder 2514)
      - Friends, Walter, Dorothy C., 1955-1961 (Box 160, Folder 2515)
      - Interests, college classes and classmates, 1942-1968 (Box 160, Folder 2516)
      - Interests, house plans, undated (Box 160, Folder 2517-2518)
      - Interests, poems and rhymes, 1937-1956, undated (Box 160, Folder 2519)
      - Writings, 1916-1933, undated (Box 161, Folder 2520-2522)
      - Writings, notes on chimps, 1932-1933 (Box 161, Folder 2523)
      - Writings, notes on chimp babies, 1938 (Box 161, Folder 2524)
      - Writings, publications, 1904-1935 (Box 161, Folder 2525)
      - Writings, verse, 1943-1964, undated (Box 161, Folder 2526)
      - Writings, bound typescript "Yale in Florida 1929-1939" and "Planting the Laboratories in Orange Park" (Box 161, Folder 2527-2528)
      - Yerkes Laboratories of Primate Biology, notes on planting, 1930-1933 (Box 161, Folder 2529)
      - Yerkes Laboratories of Primate Biology, clippings on Florida history, 1952-1966 (Box 161, Folder 2530)
    - Yerkes, Catharine Martindale, 1945-1955 (Box 161, Folder 2531)
    - Yerkes, Catherine Noyes, 1941-1948, undated (Box 161, Folder 2532)
    - Yerkes, David Norton, 1917-1955 (Box 162, Folder 2533-2534)
      - Yerkes, David Norton and Yerkes, Catharine Martindale, European trips, 1950, 1953 (Box 162, Folder 2543)
      - Military service, 1942-1947 (Box 162, Folder 2544)
      - Sketch books, 1929-1935 (Box 162, Folder 2545-2546)
    - Yerkes, Robert Mearns
      - Birthday letters, 1899-1936 (Box 162, Folder 2547)
      - to Ada W. Yerkes, 1901-1917 (Box 163, Folder 2548-2560)
      - to Ada W. and children, 1918-1955 (Box 163, Folder 2561-2566)
      - to Ada W. Yerkes, 1924-1948 (Box 164, Folder 2567-2578)
      - to David N. Yerkes, 1929-1947 (Box 164, Folder 2579-2580)
      - to Roberta W. Yerkes, 1920-1924 (Box 164, Folder 2581)
      - to Roberta W. Yerkes, 1925-1955 (Box 165, Folder 2582-2592)
    - Yerkes, Roberta Watterson, 1917-1938 (Box 165, Folder 2593)
  - Family: Relatives
    - Baldwin, Jennie and Elizabeth to Susanna Yerkes, 1912 (Box 165, Folder 2594)
    - Beatty Family, 1903-1975 (Box 165, Folder 2595)
    - Carr genealogy, 1946 (Box 165, Folder 2596)
    - Carrell family, 1904-1954 (Box 165, Folder 2597-2599)
    - Carrell genealogy, 1899, undated (Box 165, Folder 2600)
    - Cousins: Susanna Baily, Florence E. Ramsey, Anna F. Slack, 1899-1907 (Box 165, Folder 2601)
    - Diebitsch, Emil, 1903-1949 (Box 166, Folder 2602-2603)
    - Diebitach, Roberta W. and Peary, Josephine Diebitsch, 1903-1939 (Box 166, Folder 2604)
    - Goulard, Alexander, 1938-1940 (Box 166, Folder 2605)
    - Hughes, Merritt Yerkes, 1903-1964 (Box 166, Folder 2606)
    - Krusen, Edward Atkinson, 1898-1948 (Box 166, Folder 2607)
    - Krusen, Anna (Box 166, Folder 2607)
    - Krusen, Lizzie (Box 166, Folder 2607)
    - Krusen, Francis T., 1913-1965 (Box 166, Folder 2608)
    - Krusen, Mabel (Box 166, Folder 2608)
    - Mearns, Esther C., 1903-1926 (Box 166, Folder 2609)
    - Mearns Family, 1822-1951 (Box 166, Folder 2610)
    - Mearns Place and mill, 1946-1960 (Box 166, Folder 2611)
    - Morgan, Elinor, 1898-1974 (Box 166, Folder 2612)
    - Mumpoting, Louse, 1898-1927 (Box 166, Folder 2613)
    - Norton, Julia Page, 1905-1964 (Box 166, Folder 2614)
    - Noyes, M. Paul, 1942-1954 (Box 166, Folder 2615)
    - Watson family, 1900-1957 (Box 166, Folder 2616)